Guide to the Gödel Editorial Project Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Gödel Editorial Project records
1930-2001
1978-2001
SC0740
Dawson, Cheryl A.
Dawson, John W. (John William), 1944-
Feferman, Solomon.
Kleene, Stephen Cole, 1909-1994
Kreisel, Georg, 1923-
Moore, Gregory H.
Solovay, Robert.
Van Heijenoort, Jean, 1912-1986
29.5 Linear feet
Collection includes photocopied source materials, correspondence of the editors, typescripts, galleys, illustrations, and other materials generated during the editing and production of Kurt Gödel's COLLECTED WORKS. Editors and others represented in the correspondence include Solomon Feferman, Jean van Heijenoort, Stephen C. Kleene, John W. Dawson, Cheryl A. Dawson, Gregory H. Moore, Robert Solovay, and Georg Kreisel.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes photocopied source materials, correspondence of the editors, typescripts, galleys, illustrations, and other materials generated during the editing and production of Kurt Gödel's COLLECTED WORKS. Editors and others represented in the correspondence include Solomon Feferman, Jean van Heijenoort, Stephen C. Kleene, John W. Dawson, Cheryl A. Dawson, Gregory H. Moore, Robert Solovay, and Georg Kreisel.
Access Terms
Godel, Kurt.; Logic, Symbolic and Mathematical.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Front Material (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Final Checklist (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Illustrations (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Nachlass Overview (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Gödel's Gabelsberger (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - *1930c Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Introductory Note to *1930c (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - *1930c Konigsberg (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Unpublished Lecture on the Completeness of the Functional Calculus (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - *1930c Konigsberg Translation (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - *1930c Textual Notes (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - *1931? Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Introductory Note to *1931? (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - *1931? "Uber unentscheidbare Satze" (Original German) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - *1931? "On undecidable sentences" (English Translation) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - *1933o Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Introductory Note to *1933o (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - *1933o "The present situation in the foundations of mathematics" (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - *1930o References and Textual Notes (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - *1933? Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Introductory Note to *1933? (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - *1933? "Simplified proof of a theorem of Steinitz" (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - *1933? References and Textual Notes (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Zilsel "Konzept" (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Zilsel – Photocopy of Original Shorthand (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Zilsel – Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Introductory Note to *1938a (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - *1938a "Votrag bei Zilsel" (Original German) (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - *1938a "Lecture at Zilsel's" (English Translation) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - *1938a Old Versions (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Zilsel Transcription (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Notes on "Zusammenkunft bei Zilsel" (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - *1938a References and Textual Notes (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - *1939b Correspondence – Gottinger Lecture (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Introductory Notes to *1939b and *1940a (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - *1939b "Vortrag Gottingen" (Original German) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - *1939b "Lecture at Gottingen" (English Translation) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Gottingen Lecture Typescripts (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Gottingen – Photocopy of Shorthand Original (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - *1939b References and Textual Notes (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - *193? Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Introductory Note to *193? (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - *193? "Undecidable diophantine propositions" (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - *193? References and Textual Notes (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - *1940a Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - *1940a "Lecture on the consistency of the continuum hypothesis" (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - *1940a Typescript (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - *1940a References and Textual Notes (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - *1941 Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Introductory Note to *1941 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - *1941 "In what sense is intuitionistic logic constructive?" (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Yale Lecture concerning *1941 – 15 April 1941 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - *1941 Manuscript (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - *1941 References and Textual Notes (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - *1946/9 Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Introductory Note to *1946/9 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - *1946/9 Kant and Relativity– Manuscript A (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - *1946/9 Kant and Relativity– Manuscript B (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - *1946/9 Kant and Relativity– Manuscript C (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - *1946/9-B2 "Some observations about the relationship between theory of relativity and Kanitan philosophy" (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - *1946/9-B2 Typescripts (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Corrections to *1946/9-B2 Manuscript B (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - *1946/9-C1 "Some observations about the relationship between theory of relativity and Kantian philosophy" (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Corrections *1946/9-C1 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - *1946/9-C1 Typescripts (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - *1946/9-B2 and *1946/9-C1 "Barbed Wire Versions" (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - *1946/9 Textual Notes (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - *1946/9 References (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Kant-Relativity Draft MSS# 040416 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Kant-Relativity Draft MSS# 040417 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Kant-Relativity Draft MSS# 040418 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - *1949b Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Introductory Note to *1949b (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - *1949b "Lecture on rotating universes" (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - *1949b "Lecture on rotating universes" Manuscript (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - *1949b References and Textual Notes (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - *1951 "Gibbs Lecture" Introductory Note and Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - *1951 "Gibbs Lecture" & Manuscript (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - *1951 References and Textual Notes (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - *1953/9 Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Introductory Note to*1953/9 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - *1953/9-I "Is mathematics syntax of language?" (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - *1953/9-II "Is mathematics syntax of language?" (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - *1953/9-III "Is mathematics syntax of language?" (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - *1953/9-III "Is mathematics syntax of language?" (2of 2) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - *1953/9-III "Is mathematics syntax of language?" – Original Notes (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - *1953/9-IV "Is mathematics syntax of language?" (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - *1953/9-V"Is mathematics syntax of language?" (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - *1953/9-V and VI "Is mathematics syntax of language?" (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - *1953/9 References and Textual Notes (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - *1961/? Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Introductory Note to *1961/? (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - *1961/? Supporting Materials (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - *1961/? "The modern development of the foundations of mathematics in the light of philosophy" (Original German) (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - *1961/? "The modern development of the foundations of mathematics in the light of philosophy" (English Translation) (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - *1961/? "The modern development of the foundations of mathematics in the light of philosophy" – Original Notes (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - *1961/? Textual Notes (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - *1961/? References (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - *1970 Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Introductory Note to*1970 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - *1970 "Ontological proof" (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - *1970 References and Textual Notes (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - *1970a,b,c Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Solonay Introductory Note to *1970a,b,c (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - *1970a "Scales of functions" (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - *1970a,b,c Supplementary Material (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - *1970a,b,c Textual Notes (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - *1970a,b,c References (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - *1970b "Scales of functions II" (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - *1970c "Scales of functions III" (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Appendix A (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Appendix B (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - *1970 excerpt: Max-Phil XIV (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Textual Notes and Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - General Textual Notes (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - References (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Concerning References (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Addenda and Corrigenda (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Index (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Indices to References (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Complete Manuscript (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Complete Manuscript (2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Corrections to Preface and References – October 1993 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Corrections to Complete Manuscript – December 1993 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Last Corrected Pages (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - General Proofreading – Messages (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Volume II – Issues (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Volume III – General (through 1992) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Volume III – references (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Records, Accession ARCH-2005-262
  File titles beginning with a date are referring to Gödel's work of that date.
  - "Books and Journals in the Nachlass of Kurt Gödel" compiled by Cheryl A. Dawson, July 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "The Papers of Kurt Gödel, an Inventory," John W. Dawson, July 1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - TEX status, 1984-85 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1929 + trans [translation] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1930 + trans (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1930a + trans (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1931 + trans (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1930b + trans (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1931a + trans (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1931b + trans (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1931c + trans (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1931d + trans (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1931e + trans (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1931f + trans (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1931g + trans (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1932 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1932a + trans (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1932b + trans (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1932c + trans (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1932d + trans (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1932e + trans (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1932f + trans (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 1932g + trans (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1932h + trans (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 19321 + trans (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 1932j + trans (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 1932k + trans (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 1932l + trans (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 1932m + trans (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 1932n + trans (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 1932o + trans (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 1933 + trans (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 1933 + trans (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 1933a + trans (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - 1933b + trans (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - 1933c + trans (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 1933d + trans (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 1933e + trans (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 1933h + trans (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 1933i + trans (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - 1933j + trans (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - 1933k + trans (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - 1933l + trans (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - 1933m + trans (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - 1933n + trans (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - 1934 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - 1934a + trans (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - 1934b + trans (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - 1934d + trans (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - 1934e + trans (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - 1934f + trans (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - 1935 + trans (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - 1935a + trans (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - 1935b + trans (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - 1935c + trans (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - 1936 + trans (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - 1936a + trans (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - 1936b + trans (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - 1938 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - 1939 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - 1939a (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - 1940 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - 1944 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - 1946 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - 1947 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - 1949 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - 1949a + (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - 1952 (?) (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - 1958 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - 1972a (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Reviews (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - References (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Gödel correspondence (responses to the call for correspondence from Gödel 1982) (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Correspondence [letter to Feferman from John, 1987, with attachments] (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Translations of Gödel-Bernays correspondence (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Typescripts of Gödel-Bernays and Gödel-Carnap correspondence (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Bernays-Gödel correspondence 1930-31 (photocopies) (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Gödel-Bernays correspondence, 1930s-60s (photocopies) (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Re Gödel-Bernays correspondence (photocopies) (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Gödel-Bernays correspondence (photocopies) (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Gödel-Herbrand correspondence (JvH's file) (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Gödel-Ulam correspondence 1956-73 (photocopies) (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Gödel correspondence with van Heijenoort 1960s (photocopies) (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Dreben-Gödel correspondence (photocopies) (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Dreben-Gödel correspondence (photocopies) (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Gödel-von Neumann correspondence (copies) (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Integrated TEX files for 1944-1972 items, done in 1985 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Dreben and van Heijenoort. Notes on Gödel 1929/30, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Dreben / van Heijenoort. Notes on Gödel 1929/30, final MS. + TEX (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - van Heijenoort / Dreben. Notes on Gödel 1929/30 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - van Heijenoort. Notes on Gödel 1929/30 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - S. C. Kleene re: 1931, 1934 items, notes and revisions, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - S. C. Kleene re: 1931, 1934 (Sept. 1983 on) (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Kleene – notes on 1930b, 1931, 1932b, 1934 - 1983 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - TEX – Kleene notes for 1931 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Feferman – Introductory note to 1931c, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Kleene – 1931 (etc.) Aug.-Nov. 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Dawson – notes on 1931a etc. 1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Quine – notes on Gödel's short notes 1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Troelstra – note on 1932, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Goldfarb – notes on Gödel 1932a, 1933i + revisions, 1983-84 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Kleene – note on 1932d, 1934e, 1936b, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Webb – notes on G's geometry papers, 1933b etc., 1983-85 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Troelstra – notes on Gödel 1933e, f, 1984-85 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Royden – notes (?) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Kleene – 1934 - TEX (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Kleene – notes on Gödel 1934, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Vaught – notes on Gödel 1934c, 1935, 1984-85 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Solovay – notes on Gödel 1938, 1939a, 1940, 1983-85 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Dawson – intro note on 1936 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Parikh – notes on 1936a, 1983-85 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Parsons – notes on 1944 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Parsons – notes on 1946, 1983-85 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Hawking – notes on Gödel 1949, 1950, 1983-85 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Stein – notes on Gödel 1949a, 1983-85 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Translation of 1958, semi-final version (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Translation of 1958 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Troelstra – notes for 1958/1972 TEX version (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Troelstra – notes for 1958/1972 08/84 version (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Troelstra – notes for 1958/1972 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Troelstra – notes for 1958 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Troelstra – notes for 1958/1972 revised (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Dialectica paper – misc. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Gödel chronology (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Guidelines to authors and original invitations, 1982-83 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Introductory notes – letters to authors after 1st draft (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Penultimate letters to authors of notes (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - G. Project invoices 1981/82 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Gödel Project budgetary 1986-87 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Gödel Project expenses 1985/86 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Gödel Project foreign editions (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Oxford Press contract/agreement 1983 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Oxford new contract, Vol. II, Vol. III? (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - OUP [Oxford Univ. Press] – publicity, etc., Vol. II, III (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - OUP – publicity, etc., Vol. I (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Gödel Project – Oxford Press Vol. I (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Gödel Works Vol. I - reviews (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Gödel Project Vol I – OUP publicity (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Gödel Project – legal matters, copyright memo 1983 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Oxford Press – agreement, correspondence (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Gödel Project – editorial C.V's (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Gödel Project – editorial correspondence 1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Estimates of lengths (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Moore, Gregory – correspondence 1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Title page and cover – experiments (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Letters on Gödel volume 1986 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - RS [Soloway] file – correspondence (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Dawson – annotated bibliography, 1981-82 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - TEX – references + Dawson bibliography [only contains the bibliography (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - JvH file [van Heijenoort] (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - JD [Dawson] file (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Moore on Russell [Moore's paper "Russell's Paradox: A Reappraisal of its Origins" 1985] (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - GM [Moore] file, correspondence and notes from conversations, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - SCK [Kleene] file, correspondence and notes from conversations, 1984-86 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - GK [Kreisel] – JvH 1984 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Kreisel – notes on three undated notes (1972a) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - From Kohler and Schimanovich, 1985-86 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Finalizing volume 1, summer 1985 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - NSF Proposal – work up (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - NSF Proposal – work up (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - NSF Proposal – assorted (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - NSF – Gödel Project award (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - G. Project funding (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - G. Project – initial funding efforts (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - NSF – proposal addenda work up (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Editorial Board – C.V.'s (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - NSF Proposal - final (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - TEX – proof reading correspondence, 1984-85 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Gödel Project Editorial – May/June 1985 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Gödel Project Editorial – May-December 1984 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - G. Project Ed. Group notes and correspondence Jan.-Feb. 1984 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - G. Project Ed. Group notes and correspondence Sept. 1983-Feb. 1984 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Gödel Project Princeton meeting 10/11/83 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Gödel Project Editorial notes and correspondence May-October 1983 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Gödel Project Editorial notes and correspondence Nov. 1982-July 1983 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Gödel Project Editorial notes and correspondence Aug.-Dec. 1982 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Gödel Project Editorial correspondence April-July 1982 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Gödel Project organizationa letters to Edit. Board 5/12/82 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Gödel Project Editorial correspondence Jan.-April 1982 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Gödel Project Pre-organizational correspondence 1978-1981 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Gödel Project 1982 Format/Styles questions (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Gödel Project I.A.S. organization meeting (core ed. group) July 1982 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Gödel Project Editorial notes, correspondence May-Aug. 1982 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Gödel Project – organizational summer 1982 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Moore – draft transcription of Gödel's 38-39 lectures (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Arbeitshefte – Indexes (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Gödel – Gabelsberger fragment (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Translations – questions (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Draft translations (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Kreisel correspondence [actually contains 2 papers: "Frege's Foundations and Intuitionistic Logic" and "Gödels Ambivalenz zur intuitionistischen Logik"] (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Princeton Press – copyright negations re 1940 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Nagayama, Tadashi – correspndence, 1984-85 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Nagayama – Gabelsberger translation (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Gödel Project expenses 1982-84 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Gödel Project expenses (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Expenses (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Gödel Project – report to ASL 12/22/83 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Gödel Project – funding correspondence 1983 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Expenses, NSF and Sloan grants from 8/20/84 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Gödel Project Publisher's final responses (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Gödel Project – letters to publishers (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Gödel II – references, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Dawson – Vol. III issues (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Volume III general planning and organization (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Gödel – Konigsberg lecture on completeness plus translation and textual notes (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - *1930? (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Hahn: Vienna seminar notes (Gödel's contributions) *1931/2 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - *1933? (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - *1933g (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - *1937 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Vortrag by Zilsel *1938a (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Vortrag by Zilsel *1938a (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Notre Dame seminar on logic *1939c (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - *1938c (040181) (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - *1938c (040180) (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - *1938c (040182) (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - *1939d Gottingen Vortrag transcription/translation (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Gödel Gottingen lecture *1939d (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - *193?a Theorem on Real Functions (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Some Observations.. theory of relativity.. .Kantian philosophy *1946/9 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - *1949b, *1950 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - *1949b (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - *1950 – ICM lecture "Rotating universes in general relativity theory" (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Gödel – text of Gibbs Lecture *1950 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - *1953/9 "Is mathematics syntax of language?" (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - *1961/? "The modern development of the foundations of math in the light of philosophy" (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - *1970 Ontologischer Beweis (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - *1970c (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - *1970b Scales of Functions II (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - *1970a (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - *1970? Schemes of ramification (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Dawson – inventory of G. Nachlass 1984 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Books and Journals in Gödel's Nachlass 1984 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Microfilm copies of Gödel's Nachlass papers (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Headings in "Logic and Foundations" from the Arbeitshefte (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Gödel – transcription from the Arbeitshefte (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Herbrand transcripts (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Max-Phil notebook transcriptions (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Other shorthand transcriptions (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Addenda and Corrigenda – Gödel Works Vol. I (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Gödel – independent AC (?) notes (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - B. J. Lucas re Gödel/Parry, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Prefatory material Vol. II (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Permissions statement Vol. II (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Volume II proof reading correspondence 1987-88 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Moore material 5/20/88 and vol. II proof reading (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Final corrections to IN [introductory notes] 38, 39, 39a, 40 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Solovay – IN to 1938-40 (TEX) (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Solovay – Introd. Note to 1938-1940 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Solovay – Introd. Note extra copies (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Solovay 1938 [re his introductory note to], 1985 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Final corrections to IN 44 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Parsons – notes on 1944, 1983-85 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Parsons – changes in note for 1944 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Parsons – note on 1944 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Gödel 1944 Emendations (prep. by JvH) (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Final corrections to IN 46 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Final corrections to IN 47, 64 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence re IN 47, 64 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Moore – Introductory note to Gödel 1947 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Final corrections to Gödel 1947 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Final corrections to IN 49, 52 (Box 5, Folder 27)